Esther Chenang'at Lonyangapuo Web Developer

chenalonya@gmail.com | +254703349526 | Nairobi, Kenya | Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), SQL, Typescript, PHP

Frameworks: SASS, LESS, Tailwind CSS, Angular, React, Next.Js, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js

Tools: VSCode, Linux, npm, Webpack, git, Postman, MongoDB, Postman, Mongoose, Jest, Karma, Jasmine General: WordPress, Shopify, Squarespace, Elementor, Divi, FSE, Advanced Custom Fields, SEO Optimization using Google Search Console, Google Analytics, Ahrefs; Digital Marketing, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere, Procreate, Canva, Figma, Blender, UnrealEngine, ClickFunnels, Zapier, Active Campaigns

SELECTED PROJECTS

MERN Stack Projects

Live: Herculean Strength Code: Github Link

This is a powerlifting workout A.I. app based on the principles of Boris Sheiko's training methods. The app takes into account a user's stats and generates a workout that enables the user to reach their competitive goals. The training models are built on the logic that I wrote to make the program adaptive.

Live: Soma App Code: Github Link

A full stack MERN app that has been developed to make it easier for bibliophiles to discover, save and download their favourite books in EPUB and audiobook form. Data is pulled from a renown book website, with book search and display being made through API calls. Allows user registration, rating and access to download books.

MEAN Stack Projects

Live: The Freaky Link Code: Github Link

A full stack, fully functional MEAN stack project. It was created for my existing business, live version is built under WordPress CMS. Please note it takes the website some time to load up as it is hosted on the free plan.

Live: Weatherzone Code: Github Link

A full-stack Angular weather forecasting application. It offers full search functionality and 3-day forecasting. Please note it takes the website some time to load up as it is hosted on the free plan.

WordPress Experience

Nalela Hair and Beauty

An e-commerce website for my cosmetics business. Built using Elementor. Fully optimized SEO, server & security. **ESI PEO**

A website for a Professional Employer Company (PEO) based in Texas. Responsible for all Content, design, build, and SEO optimization, as well as ongoing maintenance.

Aussie Tinting

A website for a client based in Australia that required a way to advertise their business, collect leads, and display their blog. It has fully optimized SEO, server management and robust security.

Royalty Insurance

A website built for an insurance company based in the USA. Responsible for all Content, design, build, and SEO optimization, as well as ongoing maintenance.

Austin Limo Rentals

A website built for Limousine rentals. It is part of a catalogue of different limo booking websites that I have built for my employer DIQSEO.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DIQ SEO Nov. 2024 – Current

- Developed and maintained responsive websites for clients
- Performed technical on and off page SEO optimizations for clients.
- Performed various marketing objectives to meet client goals, such as running ads and campaigns
- Managed servers and databases for multiple websites
- Performed bug fixes, and any technical fixes that were required for server or website optimization
- Managed a team of two developers and marketers
- Developed themes, API, and plug-ins to meet various client needs
- Created monthly reports to clients on builds and fixes that have been done to meet their needs
- Created AI prompts and engines to make work easier in terms of content and marketing work

Turnkey Tinting

March. 2024 – Sep. 2024

Wordpress Developer

Australia, Remote

- Developed and maintained responsive websites for clients launching their window tinting businesses.
- Managed servers and databases for multiple websites using Docker, Cloudways, DigitalOcean, MariaDB & more
- Collaborated with design teams to integrate designs while focusing on Web Accessibility.
- Demonstrated expertise in such as React and PHP to build custom themes and plugins to meet business needs.
- Managed SEO and marketing operations by harnessing Google Tag Manager, Analytics, as well as various pixels.

Marketer Granted Dec. 2023 – March 2024

Wordpress Developer

USA, Remote

- Developed and maintained responsive web solutions using ClickFunnels, ensuring seamless user experiences.
- Implemented efficient marketing automations to streamline processes and enhance productivity.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate web development strategies aligned with marketing objectives.
- Demonstrated expertise in front-end technologies such as Angular with TypeScript and React for versatile development tasks.

Nalela Hair and Beauty

Feb. 2020 – Current

CEO & CTO

Nairobi, Kenya

- Built, planned the website architecture, maintained and handled debugging a WordPress website designed for the business by learning to manage databases, PHP, SEO and servers.
- Maintained back-end management tasks like database and server integration with regular testing and troubleshooting of the website to ensure optimum live performance and peak security.
- Implemented targeted digital marketing campaigns and optimized SEO practices to increase brand awareness and customer engagement, resulting in a massive growth in social media followers and website traffic.
- Maintained meticulous financial records, managing all accounting tasks including budgeting, forecasting, tax filings, and vendor payments within stipulated deadlines.

Dagat Company Limited

Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2022

CEO & CFO

Kitui, Kenya

- Oversaw the growth of a stone quarrying company from a small 10-tonne-per-hour crusher to a booming 50-tonne-per-hour operation, resulting in a 400% increase in production capacity.
- Strategized and executed daily sales efforts, leading to an average monthly revenue of \$30K and securing long-term contracts with major construction companies in the region.
- Streamlined administrative processes by implementing Microsoft Excel and various accounting software like Quickbooks for financial record keeping, resulting in a 30% reduction in operational costs.
- Oversaw a staff of 27 people by maintaining a friendly, collaborative yet professional environment.

2D/3D Artist Sep. 2017 – Dec. 2022

Freelance Artist-Portfolio

Remote

- Created art classes that are uploaded on the website Skillshare as well as Udemy. As of the end of 2023, the classes had over 400 students and still accumulate students daily.
- Leveraged social media platforms such as Instagram and Facebook to build a strong online presence
- Created artwork for clients using technologies such as Illustrator, Photoshop, Procreate, Krita, and Blender.

EDUCATION

MBA

The Odin Project Jan. 2023 - Jul. 2023

Web Development Training Bootcamp

Remote

 HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, SQL, React, Angular, Next.js, Node.js, Express, Jest Karma, APIs design, MongoDB, webpack, git, responsive design, cross-browser compatibility and UI/UX design principles.

University of the People

Sep. 2021 - Current

Remote

Masters in Business Administration.

University Of Nairobi

Sep. 2012 - Sep. 2017

Nairobi, Kenya

Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering

- First Class Honors; 4.0 GPA
- Winner of Patrick Maimba Vision 2030 Social and Political Pillar in Nairobi University, 2017
- Winner of Patrick Maimba Vision 2030 Social Pillar in Nairobi University, 2016
- Captain of Swimming team that won in East African Games 2014

AWARDS, SKILLS, LANGUAGES & INTERESTS

Awards: 2022 - Winner of Kamkunji Kenya Strongest Woman; Winner Kenya Open Powerlifting

2021 - Winner of Misuli Kenya Strongest Woman Competition

2017 - Winner of Patrick Maimba Vision 2030 Social and Political Pillar at Nairobi University

2016 - Winner of Patrick Maimba Vision 2030 Social Pillar at Nairobi University

2011 - Top Female Student in the National Ranking of Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

- **Skills:** Problem-solving, communication, meeting deadlines, attention to detail, open source projects
- Languages: English, Swahili, Spanish (advanced), French (intermediate), German (intermediate)
- Interests: Sci-Fi/Horror Books, Powerlifting, Swimming, Art, Travel, It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia